

# NISAL SANDARUWAN

## Chef de Partie

## CONTACT

- +94 76 8770 360
- nisalcrypto22@gmail.com
- 388/B 1 , A. William Road, Miriswaththa, Balangoda

## OTHER DETAILS

- DOB 29.04.2000
- NIC 200012000335
- Nation Sinhala
- Religion Buddhist
- Civil Status Non Married

#### SKILLS

- Culinary Expertise
- Menu Development
- Food Presentation
- Team Leadership
- Inventory Management
- Time Management
- Food Safety
- Cost Control
- Problem-Solving
- Customer Focus

## ABOUT ME

Passionate and skilled Chef de Partie with 7 years of experience in high-volume kitchens and fine dining establishments. Adept at leading a team, maintaining quality standards, and ensuring timely food preparation. A creative professional with a strong dedication to delivering exceptional culinary experiences.

## EXPERIENCE

Chef de Partie 2024 - Present

### Sennya Resorts - Belihuloya

- Manage a specific kitchen section (Cold, Hot & Pastry)
- Prepare and present dishes to high standards, ensuring consistency and quality.
- Train and mentor junior chefs and kitchen staff.

Demi chef 2024 - 2022

#### Sennya Resorts - Belihuloya

- Menu Design and Development
- Maintain inventory levels and minimize waste through efficient stock rotation.

1st Commis 2022-2021

#### Sennya Resorts - Belihuloya

- Collaborate with the Head Chef on menu updates and specials.
- Maintain inventory levels and minimize waste through efficient stock rotation.

2nd Commis 2021 - 2020

#### Sennya Resorts - Belihuloya

## EDUCATION

• G.C.E. A/L

Art Stream | Dharmananda Collage Balangoda

• G.C.E. O/L

Passed | Dharmananda Collage

Balangoda

## CERTIFICATION

 National Apprentice and Industrial Training Authority (NAITA)

Certified in

- 1. Cold Kitchen
- 2. Hot Kitchen
- 3. Pastry Kitchen

## SOFT SKILLS

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Adaptability
- Time Management
- Creativity
- Attention to Detail
- Work Under Pressure
- Conflict Resolution
- Musician & Guitarist

## LANGUAGE

- Sinhala
- English

3rd Commis 2020 - 2019

Belihiloya Rest House by Ceylon Hotels Corporation

- Belihuloya

Trainee Kitchen 2019

Orient Hotel - Bandarawela

## REFERENCES

## Mr. Isuru Aththanayake

General Manager Sennya Resorts

**Phone:** +94 77 313 8844 **Email:** gm@sennyaresorts.com

#### Mr. Dushmantha Kumara

Exe: Chef

The Rustic Kitchen

Phone: +94 71 750 2925

Email: dushmantha137@gmail.com